<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Java API for Microsoft Intellitype</title>
    <author email="info.AT.melloware.DOT.com">Emil A Lefkof III</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="JIntellitype API">

      <subsection name="Introduction">
      <p>
        JIntellitype is a Java API for interacting with Microsoft Intellitype 
        commands as well as registering for Global Hotkeys in your Java application.  
        The API is a Java JNI library that uses a C++ DLL to do all the communication
        with Windows.   <strong>NOTE:</strong> This library ONLY works on Windows.  If
		you are looking for a Linux version please see <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/jxgrabkey/">JxGrabKey</a> project on Sourceforge.
      </p>
       </subsection>

      <subsection name="Hotkeys">
        <p>
          Have you ever wanted to have CTRL+SHIFT+G maximize your Swing application 
          on the desktop? Even if that application did not have focus?  Well, now you can! By
          registering a Windows Hotkey combination, your application will be alerted 
          when the combination you select is pressed anywhere in Windows.  Windows has the
          API call <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/default.asp?url=/library/en-us/winui/winui/windowsuserinterface/userinput/keyboardinput/keyboardinputreference/keyboardinputfunctions/registerhotkey.asp">RegisterHotKey</a>
          for registering a global hotkey combination so that your app receives that message
          no matter what else you are doing or even if your application has focus.  This is
          a commonly requested feature in Java that has now been implemented by JIntellitype.
          
          Check out the <a href="quick-start.html">Quick Start Guide</a> for an example on how to use JIntellitype.
        </p>

      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Intellitype">

        <p>
          Have you ever wanted your Java application to react to those special Play, Pause, 
          Stop keys on some newer keyboards like Winamp and Windows Media Player do?  Ever wonder how they do it? 
          If you want your application to "listen" for those special keys, now you can with JIntellitype!  
          Just register an IntellitypeListener and you will be notified when those messages are received.   
          To read more about these special commands see the <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/default.asp?url=/library/en-us/winui/winui/windowsuserinterface/userinput/keyboardinput/keyboardinputreference/keyboardinputmessages/wm_appcommand.asp">MSDN Documentation</a>
          about the Intellitype commands.
          
          Check out the <a href="quick-start.html">Quick Start Guide</a> for an example on how to use JIntellitype.
        </p>

      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Donate">
        <p>
          Although JIntellitype is open source, small financial donations are appreciated.  By supporting Melloware, you help fund the development
          (mainly development tools and internet access etc) of Melloware's Software.   To send money, simply click on the PayPal icon to the left. 
        </p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Applications Using JIntellitype">
        <p>
          <a href="http://melloware.com/products/jukes/index.html">Jukes</a> cross platform music player and organizer.
        </p>
        <p>
          <a href="http://jajuk.sourceforge.net">JaJuk</a> cross platform swiss army knife music player including DJ mode and much more!
        </p>
        <p>
          <a href="http://www.c2tn.de">C2TN</a> C2TN is the first RSS Reader which integrates completely into your desktop.
        </p>
		  <p>
          <a href="http://www.atunes.org/">aTunes</a> aTunes is a GPL audio player and manager.
        </p>
		<p>
          <a href="http://www.topkeys.net">Topkeys</a> emulates the mouse using the keyboard.
        </p>
		<p>
          <a href="http://kolovos.wiki.sourceforge.net/MiniGen">MiniGen</a> is a program that can generate text in any Windows-based (tested on XP/Vista) application based on the currently selected text in a non-invasive manner.
        </p>
        <p>
          <a href="http://xtrememp.sourceforge.net/">Xtreme Media Player</a>  is a free cross-platform media player.
        </p>
		<p>
          <a href="http://github.com/marnix/mytime/tree/master">MyTime</a> is a simple time tracker, mostly controlled through the tray icon.
        </p>
		<p>
          <a href="http://radis.sourceforge.net/">RadiS</a> is a cool-looking mouse menu that opens upon a global hot-key. Allows sub-menus which will be displayed in an adjacent partly circle.
        </p>
		<p>
          <a href="http://jshot.info/">JShot</a> is a free and multiplatform screen capture and uploader utility which allows you to capture a part of your screen and publish it in one step.
        </p>
		<p>
          <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/opensoundboard">OpenSoundboard</a> plays sound files (currently only .wav) when the user presses hotkeys.
        </p>
		<p>
          <a href="http://clipcomrade.sourceforge.net/">Clipcomrade</a> - simple and free open source windows clipboard manager tool
        </p>
		<p>
          <a href="http://wordoholic.com/">Wordoholic Learner</a> - a cross-platform language learning tool
        </p>
		<p>
          <a href="http://code.google.com/p/hotshots/">Hotshots</a> - Easy to use screenshot utility for Windows and Linux
        </p>
		<p>
          <a href="http://code.google.com/p/g15lastfm/">G15Lastfm</a> - Last.fm player for G15 gaming keyboard
        </p>
		<p>
          <a href="http://code.google.com/p/webapp-workplace/">webapp-workplace</a> - Web Workspace/Client to provide notifications for different web applications such as gmail, facebook, etc. 
        </p>
		<p>
          <a href="http://code.google.com/p/hawkscope/">Hawkscope</a> - is a productivity tool that allows you to access your hard drive contents quickly via system tray / menubar icon with dynamic pop-up menu. 
        </p>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Features"> 
         <ul>
            <li>Can register global hotkey combinations in Java applications in Windows </li>
            <li>Application is notified even if it does not have focus.</li>
            <li>Can react to those Play, Pause, Stop, Next, Forward Media keys like Winamp</li>
            <li>Very little code, easy to use API</li>
            <li>Examples included in <a href="xref-test/com/melloware/JIntellitypeTester.html">JIntellitypeTester.java</a></li>
         </ul>
      </subsection>

      

    </section>
<script src="http://www.google-analytics.com/urchin.js" type="text/javascript">
</script>
<script type="text/javascript">
_uacct = "UA-2908999-2";
urchinTracker();
</script>
 </body>
</document>